Find the Empress
皇后様を頼ろう
The matter of Prince of Jin's misfortune
今の騒動は
Probably hasn't spread widely
大っぴらになっておらぬ。
I, as a daughter-in-law
あたしが
Going to visit Mother
謁見すれば
Might not be stopped
阻まれはせぬはず。
Though the Empress never interferes in court matters
皇后様は朝政に干渉せぬが
She must care for her son
息子を思う心はおありのはず。
Indeed
まさしく
At this time
この局面を制するには
I'm afraid only the Empress can delay Prince of Ning
皇后様だけでしょう。
Perhaps
或いは
Chancellor Chen was right
陳相の言は正しかったか……
Sir
陳様……
Rash and hasty
落ち着け！
Rushing to be reborn
死に急ぐか？
Sir
陳様……
Your Highness
殿下
Empress
皇……皇后……
This palace's rashness
わらわ、この騒動で使いもせぬ声を上げさせ
Must have made Sir Chen laugh
陳様には笑われてしまったわ。
Empress, Mother
皇后様　母上
How dare you
何をなさったの！
Beat my son like this
我が子を打ち据え……
Prince
殿下様
Release him immediately
すぐにお放しなさい！
Hurry
さっさと放せ！！！
Everyone, leave first
早う出て行きなさい！
Mother
母上……
Aren't you leaving?
出ぬか
Waiting for me to scold you?
𠮟りを待っておれと？
You might as well scold me to vent your anger
叱っていただくだけでも……
Get out
出ていけ！
Yes
承知しました……
Prince
殿下様
I came too late
あたしが遅れました……
You three men
父子三人
Are like pressing down a gourd and a ladle pops up
どいつもこいつも
None of you let me rest easy
心休まらぬわ。
Just watched your father take medicine
さきほどはそなたの父上が薬をお飲みになったばかりと見受けしのに
And now you two brothers
次の瞬間には兄弟が
Are fighting like this
またこの騒ぎとは……！
I don't understand your schemes
わたくしにはこのややこしさが理解できぬ
You and your elder brother
兄弟二人は
Are both my flesh and blood
同じ母の子。
Sometimes
時折
I feel like a porter
母は担ぎ手の如く思うことがある。
Must balance both ends of the carrying pole
一本の棒の両端を等しく支えねばならず
Can't favor either side
片方にも偏らぬよう絶えず気を配るのじゃ。
Father's health
父上の
Is it alright?
お体は……
You know
お前も知っておろう。
Your father usually
父上は常に
Likes to mess with those elixirs
丹薬を弄り
His health was already poor
体が弱い。
With this trouble
この騒動で
He's been bedridden for days again
また数日寝込むことになるじゃろう。
Your father doesn't want to see you now
父上はお前に会いたくないと申す。
If you have something to say
もし何か言いたいなら
I'll say it for you
母が替わって申し上げよう。
Thank you, Mother
母上……
Please tell Father
どうか、父上にお伝えくださいませ……